A Guide to the Edgar Allan Poe Research Collection 1968-1982
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Edgar Allan Poe Research Collection 1968-1982
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11233
This collection contains ca. 1460 items.
There are ca. 1460 items, ca. 1968-1982, relating to the scholarship and criticism of Edgar Allan Poe.
This collection was compiled by J. Lasley Dameron.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This research material was given to the Library by J. Lasley Dameron, Department of English, University of Michigan, Memphis, Tennessee, on May 1, 1996.
Scope and Content Information
There are ca. 1460 items, ca. 1967-1982, relating to the scholarship and criticism of Edgar Allan Poe, compiled by J. Lasley Dameron. There is correspondence relating to the study Edgar Allan Poe: A Bibliography of Criticism, 1927-1967 by J. Lasley Dameron and Irby B. Cauthen, Jr. Correspondents include Stephen L. Mooney, Knoxville, Tennessee; Richard P. Benton, Department of English, Trinity College; Koh Kasegawa, Aoyama Gakuin University, Shibuya, Tokyo, Japan; John E. Reilly, Department of English, College of the Holy Cross; Hisazumi Tagiri, Tokyo, Japan; Ichigoro Uchida, Kyoritsu Women's Junior College, Tokyo, Japan; and, librarians of various institutions. Reilly is also the author of John Henry Ingram's Poe Collection at the University of Virginia. Other materials include ca. 60 reprints, 1845-1975, of essays, articles, and books of criticism on Poe; three newsletters, 1976-1976, entitled "Edgar Allan Poe Scripts"; and, an electrostatic copy of a 1942 University of Virginia thesis, "A Descriptive Bibliography of Criticism of Edgar Allan Poe, 1827-1941," by Irby Bruce Cauthen. In addition, there are ca. 1200 index cards compiled by John Cook Wyllie as a guide to Poe's critical essays (located in card file drawer #75).
Contents List
- CORRESPONDENCE AND REPRINTS
  - Correspondence and Reprints, 1850-1967, used in Poe Research 1962-1971 Feb (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and Reprints, 1831-1982, used in Poe Research 1971 Jun-1982 (Box 1)
- NEWSLETTER 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  "Edgar Allan Poe Scripts" by Frank Wuttge, Jr.
- REPRINTS
  - Reprints 1845-1973, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Reprints 1974-1980, 9 folders (Box 2)
  - Reprints 1981-1993, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Reprints n.d. (Box 3)
  - Reprints: Edgar Allan Poe... by Andre Karatson 1971 (Box 3)
- THESIS 1942, 3 folders (Box 3)
  "A Descriptive Bibliography of Criticism of Edgar Allan Poe, 1827-1941" by Irby Bruce Cauthen